Guide to the Blatchford, Potter, and Delano Family Papers 1796-1995 (bulk, 1796-1919) MS 3132
New-York Historical Society
Blatchford, Potter, and Delano family papers
1796-1995 (bulk, 1796-1919)
New-York Historical Society
MS 3132
4 Linear feet (in 2 record cartons and 2 flat boxes).
Correspondence, generally of a familial nature, and photographs, of the interrelated Blatchford, Potter, and Delano families, which included such illustrious members as U.S. Minister to the Papal States Richard Milford Blatchford (1798–1875), his son, jurist Samuel Blatchford (1820–1893), Richard's son-in-law, architect Edward Tuckerman Potter (1831–1904), and Potter's son-in-law, architect William Adams Delano (1874–1960).
Arrangement
The collection is organized in four series. Within each series, the archivist has attempted to maintain a subject's generational position within the family unit.
Series I.
Blatchford family, 1796-1865, 1895
Series II.
Potter family, 1804-1906, 1995
Series III.
Delano family, 1895-1948
Series IV.
Photograph albums, circa 1894-1935
Biographical / Historical
The three New York families represented in this collection—Blatchford, Potter, and Delano—are related through marriage. Julia Maria Blatchford (1834–1922), the daughter of diplomat Richard Milford Blatchford (1798–1875), married architect Edward Tuckerman Potter (1831–1904), a son of Episcopal Bishop Alonzo Potter (1800–1865) and grandson of longtime Union College president Eliphalet Nott (1773–1866). Among the children of Edward Tuckerman and Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter were a son, Julian Potter (1858–1913), U.S. Consul at Nassau, Bahamas, and a daughter, Louisa Millicent Windeatt Potter (1872–1962), who married (as her second husband) William Adams Delano (1874–1960) of the architectural firm Delano & Aldrich. Delano's father, Eugene (1844–1920), a banker, was a partner in Brown Brothers & Co. (now Brown Brothers Harriman & Co.).
For more on these families, their connections, and their illustrious members, see
Eliphalet Wickes Blatchford, Blatchford Memorial II: A Genealogical Record of the Family of Rev. Samuel Blatchford, D.D. With Some Mention of Allied Families (privately printed, 1912).
Craig Hanyan, "Richard Milford Blatchford." American National Biography (New York: Oxford University Press, 1999), vol. 3, 1–2.
Mark Alan Hewitt, "William Adams Delano." American National Biography (New York: Oxford University Press, 1999), vol. 6, 379–381.
Sarah Bradford Landau, Edward T. and William A. Potter, American Victorian Architects (New York: Garland Publishing, Inc., 1979).
Bruce Leslie, "Eliphalet Nott." American National Biography (New York: Oxford University Press, 1999), vol. 16, 537–538.
Charles W. McCurdy, "Samuel Blatchford." American National Biography (New York: Oxford University Press, 1999), vol. 3, 2–3.
Frank Hunter Potter, The Alonzo Potter Family (privately printed, 1923).
Lawrence Wodehouse, "Edward Tuckerman Potter." American National Biography (New York: Oxford University Press, 1999), vol. 17, 744–745.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Julia Jorgenson Shelly, 2018 (accession no. MS-2018-036).
Related Materials
A number of single Blatchford, Potter, and Delano family documents may be found through BobCat, the library's online catalog. Two larger items of interest are the William Adams Delano Collection [graphic], 1899-1949 (PR 244), and the William Adams Delano papers, 1947-1954 (MS 1204).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists chiefly of correspondence of a general, familial nature, between various members of the interrelated Blatchford, Potter, and Delano families (see the preceding Biographical / Historical note for an outline of how the three connect).
Blatchford family: Letters between members of the family established by Rev. Samuel Blatchford (1767–1828), including his son, Richard Milford Blatchford (1798–1875), an attorney who served in the New York State Assembly (1855) and as the 4th United States Minister to the Papal States (1862–1863) [see his letters from this time to his son, Samuel, Box 1, Folders 20–21]. Richard was a college friend and law partner of William H. Seward, to whom he loaned money [see Box 1, Folder 24], and a close associate of Daniel Webster [Box 1, Folder 26]. Richard's son, Samuel Blatchford (1820–1893), the eventual Associate Justice of the United States Supreme Court (1882–1893), served in 1840 as private secretary to Seward, who was then New York's 12th governor [see later correspondence with Seward, Box 1, Folder 45].
Potter family: Julia Maria Blatchford (1834–1922), a daughter of Richard Milford Blatchford, married the architect Edward Tuckerman Potter (1831–1904), whose plans for model tenements earned him awards at the World's Columbian Exposition [Box 1, Folders 72–77]. Edward was the son of Episcopal Bishop Alonzo Potter (1800–1865) [Box 1, Folders 69–71] and grandson of long-term Union College president Eliphalet Nott (1773–1866) [Box 1, Folder 68], for whom he designed the Nott Memorial on the Union College campus. The collection includes three year's worth of letters (1904-1906) from Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter to her son, Julian Potter (1858–1913) [Box 2, Folders 1–7], who was then serving as U.S. Consul at Nassau, Bahamas.
Delano family: Louisa Millicent Windeatt (Potter) Sheffield, a daughter of Edward Tuckerman and Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter, married the architect William Adams Delano (1874–1960). This portion of the collection consists mainly of letters written almost daily during the first decade of the 20th century to William by his father, the banker Eugene Delano (1844–1920), and mother, Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano (1848–1904).
Photograph albums: Three photograph albums depict various members of the Potter and Delano families at their homes (such as Muttontown Corners, the William Adams Delano estate at Syosset, Long Island), or traveling in Europe, for the years 1894 through 1935 [Box 3; Box 4; and Box 2, Folder 44].
Glass negatives.; Letters (correspondence); Photograph albums.; Lansingburgh (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Rome (Italy); Blatchford, John Samuel, 1831-; Blatchford, Richard Milford, 1798-1875; Blatchford, Samuel, 1767-1828; Blatchford, Samuel, 1820-1893; Blatchford, Thomas W. (Thomas Windeatt), 1794-1866; Delano, Eugene, 1844-1920; Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960; Nott, Eliphalet, 1773-1866; Potter, Alonzo, 1800-1865; Potter, Edward Tuckerman, 1831-1904; Potter, Julian, 1858-1913; Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852.; Delano & Aldrich; Union College (Schenectady, N.Y.); Blatchford (Family); Delano (Family); Potter family
- Series I. Blatchford family, 1796-1865, 1895
  - I.A. Rev. Samuel Blatchford (1767–1828)
    Biographical / Historical
    Presbyterian minister.
    - Letter from J. Smith, 1796 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      "J. Smith" was, possibly, John Blair Smith (1756-1799), first president of Union College, Schenectady, New York (1795-1799).
    - Letter to daughter, Mary Milford Windeatt Blatchford, 1813 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters to wife, Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford, 1817 May 15; 1824 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Biographical material, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Passage on Rev. Samuel Blatchford cut from The Bi-Centennial Celebration of the First Congregational Church and Society of Bridgeport, Connecticut, June 12th and 13th, 1895 (New Haven: Tuttle, Morehouse, and Taylor, 1895), 36-38, and illustration following 26.
  - I.B. Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford (1767–1846)
    Wife of Rev. Samuel Blatchford [I.A].
    - Letter to son, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1828 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Condolence letter on her death to the Misses Blatchford, 1846 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - I.C. Mary Milford Windeatt Blatchford (1790–1847)
    Daughter of Rev. Samuel Blatchford [I.A] and Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford [I.B].
    - Letter to nephew, Samuel Blatchford, 1830 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I.D. Richard Milford Blatchford (1798–1875)
    Attorney and political figure. Member of the New York State Assembly (1855) and 4th United States Minister to the Papal States (1862-1863). Son of Rev. Samuel Blatchford [I.A] and Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford [I.B].
    - Death notice for sister, Alicia Windeatt Blatchford (1791–1808), 1810 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chancery license, 1826 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters to wife, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1818, 1846-1847, 1850, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1827-1828 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1830, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1836-1838 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Letter of April 14, 1836 includes doodled portrait of a man on verso.
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1841, 1843-1844 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1846-1849 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1850-1853 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Letters to daughter, Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter, 1842, 1844-1846, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letter from Eliphalet Nott, 1846 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Account of monies due from William H. Seward, 1844 January 1; 1845 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letter from William H. Seward, 1855 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Letter from Daniel Webster, 1847 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - I.E. Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford (1798–1857)
    First wife of Richard Milford Blatchford [I.D].
    - Letter to mother, Mary J. Mumford, 1832 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Letters to husband, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Letters to husband, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letters to husband, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Letters to husband, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1846-1848 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Letters to husband, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1830, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1834, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1838-1839 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Letters to son, Samuel Blatchford, 1840-1841, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Letter to daughter, Mary Milford (Blatchford) Griswold, 1842 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Letters to daughter, Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter, 1845-1847 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - I.F. Samuel Blatchford (1820–1893)
    Jurist. Served in 1840 as private secretary to New York State Governor William H. Seward, his father's college friend and law partner. Judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York (1867-1878); Judge of the United States Circuit Court for the Second Circuit (1878-1882); Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States (1882-1893). Son of Richard Milford Blatchford [I.D] and Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford [I.E].
    - Letters to father, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1835, 1847, 1850-1851, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Letter of July 5, 1847 exhibited in Two Centuries of the Law: Cravath, Swaine & Moore at the New-York Historical Society, March 22 – June 9, 2019.
    - Letters to mother, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1838, 1846-1847 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Letters to aunt, Ethelinda Jane (Blatchford) Corbin, 1836, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Columbia College records, 1824-1838 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - New York State bar admission certificate, 1842 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence with William H. Seward, 1841-1844 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - I.G. Caroline Frances (Appleton) Blatchford (1817–1901)
    Wife of Samuel Blatchford [I.F].
    - Letter to mother-in-law, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1850 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - I.H. Mary Milford (Blatchford) Griswold (1823–1852)
    Daughter of Richard Milford Blatchford [I.D] and Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford [I.E].
    - Letters to father, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1835, 1840, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Letters to mother, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1840, 1846, 1850, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Letters to brother, Samuel Blatchford, 1832, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Letter to sister, Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - I.I. Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter (1834–1922)
    Daughter of Richard Milford Blatchford [I.D] and Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford [I.E]; wife of Edward Tuckerman Potter [II.C]. See also her letters to Potter family members under Sub-series II.D.
    - Letters to father, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1845-1846, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Letters to mother, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1850-1851, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Letter to brother, Samuel Blatchford, 1847 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Letter to sister-in-law, Caroline Frances (Appleton) Blatchford, 1844 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Letter to sister, Mary Milford (Blatchford) Griswold, 1847 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Letter from Caroline (LeRoy) Webster, 1845 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      Note accompanying flowers sent to Julia and her sister Ethelinda by Caroline (LeRoy) Webster (1797–1882), second wife of Daniel Webster.
    - Mumford and Potter families genealogical and heraldic information, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
      Facsimile of Mumford family bible records, and a note recording the Potter family's ancestral homes in England and their coat of arms. The donor believes these items to have originated with her great-grandmother, Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter (1834–1922).
  - I.J. Sophia Ethelinda Blatchford (1836–1908)
    - Letters to father, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1844, 1850-1851 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Letters to mother, Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford, 1850-1851, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Letter to brother, Samuel Blatchford, 1850 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - I.K. Thomas Windeatt Blatchford (1794–1866)
    Physician. Son of Rev. Samuel Blatchford [I.A] and Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford [I.B].
    - Letter to nephew, Samuel Blatchford, 1828 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - I.L. Frances (Wickes) Blatchford (1805–1875)
    Wife of John Blatchford (1799-1855); mother of John Samuel Blatchford [I.M].
    - Letters to sister-in-law, Ethelinda Jane (Blatchford) Corbin, 1840 January 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - I.M. John Samuel Blatchford (1831–1912)
    Son of John Blatchford (1799-1855) and Frances (Wickes) Blatchford [I.L].
    - Letters to aunt, Ethelinda Jane (Blatchford) Corbin, 1840 September 19; 1844 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - I.N. Ethelinda Jane (Blatchford) Corbin (1805–1879)
    - Letters to nephew, Samuel Blatchford, 1844 December 5; undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - I.O. Edgecumbe Heath Blatchford (1811–1853)
    Son of Rev. Samuel Blatchford [I.A] and Alicia (Windeatt) Blatchford [I.B].
    - Letter to brother, Richard Milford Blatchford, 1834 [1837?] October 10 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - I.P. Blatchford miscellaneous
    - Broadsides and newspaper photocopy, 1844, 1852, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      Contains:
      1. Broadside, "SUPPRESSED LETTER. With all our persuading, we cannot induce one Whig paper in or near this city to publish the latest letter of their great leader, Henry Clay. THEY DARE NOT PUBLISH IT. They have brought his kinsman and neighbor here to say that which Henry Clay says is a misrepresentation of his views. Read it." September 2, 1844, Ashland, Kentucky
      2. Broadside, "National Anniversary, July 4, 1852, at Auburn [New York]."
      3. Photostat of front page of The New York Herald, April 15, 1865, announcing "Assassination of President Lincoln."
    - Poetic and biblical verses, 1855 September 23; undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Series II. Potter family, 1804-1906, 1995
  - II.A. Eliphalet Nott (1773–1866)
    Presbyterian minister. Long-term president (1805-1866) of Union College, Schenectady, New York.
    - Correspondence with Mary Tillotson, 1804 March (Box 1, Folder 68)
      Copy of a letter from Mary Tillotson to Eliphalet Nott, offering to become the guardian of Nott's daughter, Maria, after her mother, Sarah Marie (Benedict) Nott died on 10 March 1804. With a copy of Nott's response. Maria was Sarah Maria Nott (1799-1839), who married Alonzo Potter [II.B].
  - II.B. Alonzo Potter (1800–1865)
    Episcopal Bishop of Pennsylvania. Son-in-law of Eliphalet Nott [II.A].
    - Note regarding Edward Tuckerman (1817–1886), [1842 November 9] (Box 1, Folder 69)
      Edward Tuckerman (1817-1886) was a botanist who attended Union College at Schenectady, New York, where Alonzo Potter had been Professor of Mathematics and Natural Philosophy in 1821-1826. It is unclear what relation he had, if any, to Potter, that would have led Potter to name his son Edward Tuckerman Potter.
    - Letter [photostat] to the employer of one of his sons, 1854 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Letter to son, Edward Tuckerman Potter, 1865 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - II.C. Edward Tuckerman Potter (1831–1904)
    Architect, best known for designing the Mark Twain House (1871) in Hartford, Connecticut, and Nott Memorial (1858-1879) at Union College, Schenectady, New York, in honor of his maternal grandfather, the school's long-serving president, Eliphalet Nott [II.A]. Son of Alonzo Potter [II.B].
    - Photographic portrait, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
      Cabinet card photographic portrait (4 x 6.5 inches) of Edward Tuckerman Potter, stamped on verso "Hanns Hanfstaengl / C. A. Teich / K. S. Hof-Photograph / Dresden."
    - Award photograph | American Institute medal, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      Two glass plate negatives (4.5 x 5.5 inches).
      obverse:
      AMERICAN INSTITUTE / NEW-YORK
      reverse:
      THE MEDAL OF SUPERIORITY / AWARDED / TO / Edwd. T. Potter, / For a Model of an / Improved Tenement House / 1890
    - Award photograph | World's Columbian Exposition medal, [1893] (Box 1, Folder 74)
      [full-length portrait of Christopher Columbus]
      PLUS / ULTRA / CHRISTOPHER / COLUMBUS / OCT / XII / MCCCCXCII / AUGUSTUS SAINT-GAUDENS FECIT
      WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION / IN COMMEMORATION OF THE / FOUR HUNDREDTH ANNIVERSARY / OF THE LANDING OF COLUMBUS / MDCCCCXCII - MDCCCCXCIII / TO EDW. T. POTTER
    - Award photograph | World's Columbian Commission plaque, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      One glass plate negative (6.5 x 8.5 inches).
      THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA / BY ACT OF THEIR CONGRESS HAVE AUTHORIZED / THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN COMMISSION / AT THE INTERNATIONAL EXHIBITION HELD IN THE CITY OF CHICAGO, STATE OF ILLINOIS, IN THE YEAR 1893, / TO DECREE A MEDAL FOR SPECIFIC MERIT WHICH IS SET FORTH BELOW OVER THE NAME OF AN INDIVIDUAL / JUDGE ACTING AS AN EXAMINER, UPON THE FINDING OF A BOARD OF INTERNATIONAL JUDGES, TO / EDWARD T. POTTER, NEWPORT, R.I. / EXHIBIT / A SYSTEM FOR CONCENTRATED RESIDENCES / AWARD / FOR ECONOMY, COMFORT, AND HEALTHFUL LIVING, BY RESTRICTING ROOM SPACE TO A / MINIMUM THE PLAN GIVES THE GREATES AMOUNT OF LIGHT, VENTILATION, / AND PRIVACY POSSIBLE UNDER THE LIMITATIONS / OF CONCENTRATED DWELLING.
    - [Concentrated residence studies from 1854 to 1901], circa 1902 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      A self-published volume of pamphlets, papers, and offprints, chiefly relating to Potter's designs for model tenements. It includes some of his poetry and song lyrics. See copy at Van Pelt Library, University of Pennsylvania.
    - Nott Memorial at Union College, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      Contains a brochure, "The Nott Memorial: A National Historic Landmark at Union College," and two copies of an article by Fred R. Bleakley, "Did Union College Scorn Monumental Folly? Nott," from the Wall Street Journal, March 21, 1995.
  - II.D. Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter (1834–1922)
    Wife of Edward Tuckerman Potter [II.C]; daughter of Richard Milford Blatchford [I.D] and Julia Ann (Mumford) Blatchford [I.E]. See also her letters to Blatchford family members under Sub-series I.I.
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1904 January-June (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1904 August-December (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1905 January-April (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1905 May-August (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1905 September-December (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1906 January-June (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters to son, Julian Potter, 1906 July-December (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letter to daughter-in-law, Alice (Pixley) Potter, 1904 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - II.E. Julian Potter (1858–1913)
    Banker and diplomat. Appointed U.S. Consul at Nassau, Bahamas in October 1900, serving nine years. Son of Edward Tuckerman Potter [II.C] and Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter [II.D].
    - Correspondence with John Hay, 1904 May [20], June 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters received, 1904, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cable to mother, Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter, 1905 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Announcement of birth of daughter, Julia Anne Dorothea Potter, at Nassau, Bahamas, October 24, 1905.
  - II.F. Robert Francis Potter (1864–1930)
    Son of Edward Tuckerman Potter [II.C] and Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter [II.D].
    - Letter to his maternal grandfather, Richard Milford Blatchford, [1869-1875] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - II.G. Eliphalet Nott Potter (1836–1901)
    Clergyman and 7th president (1871-1884) of Union College, Schenectady, New York. Son of Alonzo Potter [II.B].
    - Union College, 1882 September (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clipping, 1897 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      "TRINITY'S CELEBRATION. / WIDESPREAD EDUCATIONAL INFLUENCE OF THE CHURCH. / Address by the Rev. Dr. Eliphalet Nott Potter--Elaborate Decorations--A Large Number of Visitors." The New York Times, Monday, May 3, 1897.
  - II.H. Maria Louisa (Potter) Thompson (1839–1916)
    Daughter of Alonzo Potter [II.B]; wife of sculptor Launt Thompson (1833-1894).
    - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Description of a ball given by Mrs. Thompson, who lived in Italy, from an unidentified, undated newspaper: "Court Festivities at Florence. The Prince and Princess of Naples Give New Life to the Social Gayeties of the Tuscan Capital."
  - II.I. Newspaper clippings, circa 1837-1887
    - Miscellaneous clippings saved by Potter [?] family, circa 1837-1887 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series III. Delano family, 1895-1948
  - III.A. Eugene Delano (1844–1920)
    Banker; partner in Brown Brothers & Co. (now Brown Brothers Harriman & Co.).
    - Letters to wife, Suan Magoun (Adams) Delano, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1895, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1907-1908, 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Letter to son, William Adams Delano, 1919 December 25 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - III.B. Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano (1848–1904)
    Wife of Eugene Delano [III.A].
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 27)